Finding Aid for Harvey Elliot Brazer Papers 1952-1985
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Harvey Elliot Brazer Papers
1952-1985
Brazer, Harvey Elliot, 1922-
Professor of economics and research associate of the Institute of Public Administration at the University of Michigan. Correspondence and drafts of writings on subject of taxation; also correspondence from the Office of Tax Analysis.
861115 Aa 2
3 linear feet
Bentley Historical Library University of Michigan
The collection was donated by Harvey Brazer (donor no. 6328 ) in 1979 and 1987. Some materials were transferred from the records of the Institute of Public Policy Studies.
The collection is open for research.
Harvey E. Brazer was born October 18, 1922 in Montreal, Canada. He received his bachelor's degree from McGill University (1943) and his master's (1947) and doctorate (1951) both from Columbia University.
Brazer taught at Rutgers University (1947-1948), Lehigh University (1948-1950), Wayne State University (1950-1957), and at the University of Michigan (1957-1987) as a professor of economics and research associate of the Institute of Public Administration. Brazer was an active member and consultant of several professional tax, finance, and economic organizations.
The Harvey Brazer papers provide some documentation of his research activities and service on various university committees and in professional organizations. The files include correspondence, memoranda, reports and other material relating research on taxation, government expenditure and tax policy and his participation in a number of study commissions and citizens organizations including the Census Advisory Committee on State and Local Government Statistics, 1967-1969, Citizens' Income Tax Study Committee of Detroit, 1960-1961 and the National Committee on Tax Justice, 1969- 1970.
Subjects:
Taxation--United States.; University of Michigan. Dept. of Economics.; University of Michigan--Faculty.Faculty.; University of Michigan. Institute of Public Policy Studies.; United States. Office of Tax Analysis.
- Biographical
  - Miscellaneous information, 1957 (Box 1)
- Correspondence, 1951-1970
  - A, 1957-1966; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Automobile Insurance & Compensation Study, Advisory Committee to, 1969-1970 (Box 1)
  - B, 1957-1966; 3 folders (Box 1)
  - C, 1957-1966; 3 folders (Box 1)
  - California Law Review re "The Federal Individual Income Tax and the Poor,", 1968-1969 (Box 1)
  - Census Advisory Committee on State and Local Government Statistics (U.S. Dept. of Commerce), 1967-1969 (Box 1)
  - Citizens' Committee for Children of New York, 1967-1969 (Box 1)
  - Citizens' Income Tax Study Committee of Detroit, 1960-1961 (Box 1)
  - Committee on Social and Behavioral Urban Research (COSBUR), 1967-1969 (Box 1)
  - D, 1957-1966; 3 folders (Box 1)
  - E, 1957-1966; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - F, 1957-1966; 3 folders (Box 1)
  - Federal Reserve Bank of Boston, Nantucket Conference, 1970 (Box 1)
  - G, 1957-1966; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - H, 1950-1966; 3 folders (Box 1)
  - I, 1957-1966; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Interim Tax Study Committee (Box 1)
  - J, 1957-1966; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - K, 1952-1966; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - L, 1957-1966; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Mc, 1959-1966 (Box 2)
  - M, 1957-1966; 3 folders (Box 2)
  - N, 1957-1966; 3 folders (Box 2)
  - National Bureau of Economic Research, 1957-1958 (Box 2)
  - O, 1951-1966; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - P, 1957-1966; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - R, 1957-1966; 3 folders (Box 2)
  - S, 1957-1966; 4 folders (Box 2)
  - T, 1957-1966; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - U, 1957-1966 (Box 2)
  - Wisconsin, University of, Graduate School of Banking, 1969 (Box 2)
  - V, 1954-1966 (Box 2)
  - W, 1958-1966; 3 folders (Box 2)
  - XYZ, 1957-1966 (Box 2)
- Letters written by Harvey Brazer
  - 1967 (Box 2)
  - 1968 (Box 2)
  - 1969 (Box 2)
  - January-June 1970 (Box 2)
- Other Materials
  - Report, National Bureau of Economic Research concerning state and local government expenditures, 1956-1958 (Box 3)
  - Report, City Income Tax Committee (Ann Arbor), 1969 (Box 3)
  - Manuscript articles, undated; 1957-1960 (Box 3)
  - Office of Tax Analysis
    - Correspondence, 1961-1963 (Box 3)
    - Memoranda, 1961-1963 (Box 3)
- Later Correspondence, 1969-1982
  - Bernstein, Conway, and Goldman, January-December 1980 (Box 3)
  - Chippewa Valley School District, February-March 1982 (Box 3)
  - Democratic Policy Committee and Subcommittee on Taxes, March 1971-1972 (Box 3)
  - Development Alternatives, Inc., January-June 1985 (Box 3)
  - Economics Building Fire Assessment Committee, January-March 1982 (Box 3)
  - General, 1979-1981 (Box 3)
  - Geography Review Committee, February-April 1981 (Box 3)
  - Institute for Science and Technology, February-April 1979 (Box 3)
  - Levin, Sander, October 1969-September 1974 (Box 3)
  - National Committee on Tax Justice, May 1969-February 1970 (Box 3)
  - New York State Committee on the Quality, Cost, and Financing of Elementary and Secondary Education, March 1970-March 1972 (Box 3)